Finding Aid for John E. Meally Papers 1893-1949
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
John E. Meally Papers 1893-1949
Meally, John Edward, 1864-
1 linear ft.
Methodist minister; Correspondence and other papers relating primarily to his ministerial career.
851814 Aa 2
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Rev. Meally (donor no. 1747 ) and came to the library in 1946 and 1949.
The collection is open for research.
Methodist minister and secretary of the Board of Stewards of the Detroit Conference of the Methodist Episcopal Church.
The collection divides into three series: Correspondence; Ministerial Papers; and Miscellaneous.
Subjects:
Clergy--Michigan.; Meally, John Edward, 1864-; Methodist Episcopal Church--Michigan.; Methodist Episcopal Church. Detroit Conference.; Peoples' Congress of Applied Religion.; Plymouth (Mich.: Township); Superior (Washtenaw County, Mich.: Township)
Subjects - Visual Material:
Churches--Michigan--Farmington.; Dwellings--Michigan--Plymouth.; Farmington (Mich.)--Churches.; Farmington Methodist Church (Farmington, Mich.); Meally, John Edward, 1864-; Plymouth (Mich.)--Dwellings.; Teachers--Michigan--Plymouth.
Contributors:
Baldwin, C. W.; Barton, Charles Morris.; Brashares, Charles W., 1891-1982.; Cook, William Randolph, 1866-1946.; Crane, Henry Hitt, 1890-1977.; Fosdick, Harry Emerson, 1878-1969.; Johnson, Edward Shurley, 1896-; Leete, Frederick Deland, 1866-1958.; Lindsey, Ben B. (Ben Barr), 1869-1943.; Oxnam, G. Bromley (Garfield Bromley), 1891-1963; Reed, Marshall Russell, 1891-
Genre/Form:
Photographs.
- Correspondence
  The Correspondence dates from 1893 to 1949 and includes correspondence from such notables as C. W. Baldwin, Charles M. Barton, Charles W. Brashares, William R. Cook, Henry H. Crane, Harry E. Fosdick, Edward S. Johnson, Frederick D. Leete, Ben B. Lindsey, G. Bromley Oxnam, and Marshall R. Reed.
  - 1893-1949 undated, 25 folders (Box 1)
- Ministerial Papers
  Ministerial Papers includes a 1944 report of the Peoples' Congress of Applied Religion and miscellaneous other papers of the Detroit Conference of the Methodist Episcopal Church.
  - Report of the Peoples' Congress of Applied Religion, 1944 (Box 1)
  - Detroit Conference of the Methodist Episcopal Church miscellanea, 12 folders (Box 1)
- Miscellaneous
  Miscellaneous consists of personal items, financial materials relating to his work on behalf of retired ministers; scattered records of Superior Township, Washtenaw County and Plymouth Township, Wayne County, Michigan; and photographs.
  - Personal miscellanea (Box 1)
  - Record of service and payments of retired Methodist ministers, undated (Box 1)
  - Itemized expenditures, Superior Township, Washtenaw County, 1910-1911 (Box 1)
  - Census list of school children, Plymouth Township, Wayne County, 1901-1928 (Box 1)
  - Memorial record of Ann A. Meally, 1944 (Box 1)
  - Scrapbook containing letters of appreciation upon the retirement of John E. Meally, 1940 (Box 1)
  - Photographs (Box 1)
    Portrait; photo (1909) of Farmington Methodist Church; and photo (1904) of Plymouth school teachers taken outside a local residence
Selective Index to Correspondents
Baldwin, C. W
Dec. 13, 1918, June 6, 1919, July 24, 1919, Aug. 18, 1919, and Oct. 2, 1919.
Barton, Charles Morris
Sept. 16, 1919, Jan. 17, 1924, July 29, 1925, Aug. 24, 1926, Sept. 14, 1927.
Brashares, Charles W., 1891-1982.
Oct. 27, 1936, Nov. 8, 1940, Nov. 27, 1940
Cook, William Randolph, 1866-1946.
Jan. 1, 1944
Crane, Henry Hitt, 1890-1977.
Mar. 17, 1939, July 8, 1943
Fosdick, Harry Emerson, 1878-1969.
Oct. 3, 1940
Johnson, Edward Shurley, 1896-
Nov. 1, 1938
Leete, Frederick Deland, 1866-1958.
Sept. 20, 1919, July 20, 1928
Lindsey, Ben B. (Ben Barr), 1869-1943.
Mar. 2, 1910
Oxnam, G. Bromley (Garfield Bromley), 1891-1963.
Mar. 24, 1939
Reed, Marshall Russell, 1891-
Jan. 18, 1926, June 22, 1931, Apr. 5, 1939, Aug. 7, 1939